Guide to the William Reinhart papers, 1920-1993 MS2140.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
William Reinhart papers
1920-1993
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Reinhart, William Jennings Bryan
MS2140.UA
2 Linear Feet
Collection consists of photographs of and news clippings about George Washington coach William Reinhart ranging in date from 1920-1993. In addition, contains certificates, correspondence, and a scrapbook of testimonial banquet on March 29, 1955.
Box 1
Box 2
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition information is unknown.
Biographical Note
William Jennings Bryan Reinhart (1897-1971) was a basketball, football and baseball coach at GW from 1935-1942 and 1949-66. In between he served in the Navy and was the director of athletics and personal training at the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy. Born in Osborne, Missouri August 2, 1897, he went on to attain a B.A. in business administration from the University of Oregon in 1922. He was a three-sport athlete there, quarterbacking the football team in the 1920 Rose Bowl, which Harvard won 7-6.
After graduation, he continued at the U of O (1923-1935) as a staff member, concurrently as the basketball and baseball coach and an instructor of physical education. Reinhart came to GW in 1935, and coached Alphonse "Tuffy" Leemans, who went on to a Hall of Fame football career with the New York Giants, and Red Auerbach, legendary coach of the Boston Celtics, and member of the Basketball Hall of Fame. Auerbach said of Rhinehart in 1966: "He was twenty years ahead of his time and did well with the toughest schedule in the country in those days (the late 1930s). He taught me the type of basketball I coach." Reinhart's overall baseball record was 193-133; his football record was 16-17-1; and his basketball record was 316-239. Awards include the Helms Basketball Hall of Fame (1956) and the GW Hall of Fame Award (1993).
Collection Scope and Content
This collection consists of photographs and news clippings of George Washington coach William Reinhart, certificates, correspondence, and a scrapbook of testimonial banquet on March 29, 1955. The material ranges in date from 1920-93.
Scrapbooks; Photographs; Washington (D.C.); Football; Basketball; Sports; George Washington University
- Scrapbook--photos, Univ. Oregon diploma, Alpha Kappa Psi fraternity certificate, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  General note
  [From original finding aid]: (Note: due to poor condition, the scrapbook has been photocopied in its entirety and the original book leafs and most of the news clippings have been thrown away)
- Scrapbook of news clips of sporting events, 1920-1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  [From original finding aid]: (photocopies)
- Photographs--miscellaneous life of W. J. Reinhart, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Photographs, life, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Photographs--career and university sports, 1920 ca.-1959 ca. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Photographs, career and sports, 1920 ca.-1959 ca. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Fast Break Hope--Bill Reinhart and Friends,", 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  [From original finding aid]: (bound photocopies)
- News clippings of sports, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- News clippings, magazine articles of college basketball, 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondences, re: W. J. Reinhart Testimonial Banquet, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Telegrams, re: W. J. Reinhart Testimonial Banquet, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- W. J. Reinhart Testimonial Banquet--photocopies of photos and program, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  [From original finding aid]: (not all originals present in this collection)
- Articles: "Dr. Marvin's Genius Factory" from Saturday Evening Post, 05/29/1954 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Golf Prints by Anthony Revielli, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  [From original finding aid]: originals and photocopies
- Miscellaneous correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  [From original finding aid]: including letter from J. Edgar Hoover, and telegram from Frank Leahy, coach of Notre Dame
- Original newspaper clippings, 1920 ca.-1959 ca. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  [From original finding aid]: [relating to sports found in folders 8 and 9]
- Scrapbook of Testimonial Banquet, 03/29/1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  [From original finding aid]: (includes photographs)